# Sahil Johari

Pittsburgh PA 15232 | 214-458-7161 | sahiljohari12@gmail.com | LinkedIn | GitHub | Website

# **Summary of Qualifications**

Offering **2** years of experience in the full software development lifecycle. Driven to learn new technologies and share knowledge via teaching. Highly interested in working with modern web development frameworks.

- Key Competencies -

Communication | Problem solving | Teamwork | Creativity | Passion | Quick Learning | Curiosity

## **Technical Skills**

- HTML/CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, React, Python, C#, Oracle PL-SQL, MySQL
- Git, Postman, RESTful API consumption, JSON, VS Code, Adobe Photoshop

### **Education**

#### Master of Science, Computer Science

Southern Methodist University, Dallas, Texas

**Bachelor of Engineering, Information Technology** 

University of Mumbai, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India

GPA: 3.53/4.0

May 2019

June 2015 GPA: 70.13% (Final Year)

# **Professional Experience**

#### Senior Analyst - Capgemini Technology Services India Limited - India

June 2015 - June 2017

- Served an Australian airlines with a team of 8 developers to minimize their lead time by developing a .NET web
  application that automated the generation of their business-related reports
- Reduced the lead time by 80% (as reported) for the customer by generating over 125 reports and sending them directly to the airline's management via the application in its preliminary version
- **Front-end:** Developed responsive front-end modules such as login screen and homepage screen, and modernized the UI of 3 existing .NET web applications using jQuery and Bootstrap
- Back-end: Constructed a wrapper class library for sending documents as attachments via e-mail using the SMTP
   Client library in C#
- **Database:** Implemented over 18 PL-SQL stored procedures using dynamic SQL technique in collaboration with senior developers to perform database operations for the report automation tool

# **Additional Experience**

#### **Graduate Teaching Assistant**

January 2019 - April 2019

Department of Computer Science and Engineering, Southern Methodist University - Dallas, Texas

- Course: Principles of Computer Science
- Instructed undergraduate students in hands-on programming sessions conducted for a span of 8 weeks

### **Projects**

### **Document Organizer (Independent)**

July 2019 - Present

Develop a simple dashboard web application to assist the user in maintaining valid status of their important documents and notify them for timely renewals. *React.js, Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB* 

### **Movie Hub (Independent)**

June 2019 - July 2019

Built a user interface using The Movie DB API to create an online movies library. React.js, React Hooks

# **Game for Intelligent Simulated Military Opponents (Academic)**

August 2018 - December 2018

Simulated a battlefield via neuro-evolution in which two rival forces compete to win using "firing tanks" without any human aid. JavaScript, TensorFlow.js, p5.js

### Playing Snake using Deep Reinforcement Learning (Academic)

June 2018 - August 2018

Achieved game score of 7 on a 10x10 board using a Deep Q-learning Neural Network. Python, TensorFlow, Keras

#### Certifications

- Learning React.js (2018), LinkedIn, 2019
- Building RESTful Web APIs with Node.js and Express, LinkedIn, 2019
- JavaScript Essential Training, LinkedIn, 2019